Guide to the Henry deForest papers, 1898-1947
deForest, Henry papers,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Henry deForest papers, 1898-1947.
3214
Henry Pelouze deForest 1864-1948.
10.4 cubic ft.
Correspondence, pamphlets, clippings, broadsides, photographs
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence and printed material relating to fingerprinting, the history of fingerprinting in the United States, crime, and the International Society for Personal Identification. Also includes correspondence with J. Edgar Hoover. Photographs (originally used as lantern slides in lectures) about the Bertillon method of criminal investigation. Also, material pertaining to Columbia University and Cornell University; vacation journals and memorabilia; correspondence with and about Clinton Scollard; photographs of friends at Fulton, New York; clippings and correspondence concerning World War II, the Explorers' Club, and his medical practice. Also contains material concerning his pilgrimages to the shrines of St. Joseph du Mont-Royal, Our Lady of Lourdes, and St. Anne de Beaupre.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Henry Pelouze deForest (Cornell University Class of 1884), born in 1864 in Fulton, New York, was a physician who practiced medicine in New York City. He was also Secretary of the Class of 1884, Cornell University; Secretary of the Class of 1890, College of Physicians and Surgeons of Columbia University; Librarian of the Cornell Club of New York; historian of the Alpha Mu Pi Omega Medical Fraternity; major and surgeon of the 13th Coast Artillery of the New York National Guard; Political Surgeon and Chief Medical Examiner for the Municipal Civil Service Commission of New York City; and President of the International Society for Personal Identification. He invented the dactyloscope.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence and printed material relating to fingerprinting, the history of fingerprinting in the United States, crime, and the International Society for Personal Identification. Also includes correspondence with J. Edgar Hoover. Photographs (originally used as lantern slides in lectures) about the Bertillon method of criminal investigation, including a portrait of Alphonse Bertillon. Also, material pertaining to Columbia University and Cornell University; vacation journals and memorabilia; correspondence with and about Clinton Scollard; photographs of friends at Fulton, New York; clippings and correspondence concerning World War II, the Explorers' Club, and his medical practice. Also contains material concerning his pilgrimages to the shrines of St. Joseph du Mont-Royal, Our Lady of Lourdes, and St. Anne de Beaupre and a set of bookplates he designed for the Cornell Club library and other individuals and libraries. (3714)
Correspondence with classmates, other class secretaries, and Cornell University officials, photographs, newspaper clippings, and other printed material (59 volumes) concerning the activities and deaths of the members of the Class of 1884 and the "Early Eighties," a group of 1880-1889 class members; reunions of the Class of 1884, especially its 45th, 50th, 52nd, 55th, and 60th; the Class of 1884 fund; alumni trusteeship candidacies, annual Cornell dinners, and other events and business of interest to alumni; the Cornell Association of Class Secretaries; and "The Story of Cornell" bookplate, designed by De Forest and intended for use in a proposed historical department of the Cornell University Library to be known as "The Story of Cornell." Also, vital statistics (1 vol.) of class members. In addition to de Forest's correspondence with classmates, there is scattered correspondence with Carl L. Becker, John Henry Comstock, Simon Henry Gage, Hu Shih, and Howard A. Stevenson, editor of the Cornell Alumni News. (41-4-833, 41-4-1282)
A composite of mug shots, Bertillon measurements and fingerprints of Will West and William West, an infamous case that showed the importance of a fingerprint system over the Bertillon system (1901-1904)
Also one Cornell banner.
SUBJECTS
Names:
De Forest, Henry Pelouze,1864-1948.; Bertillon, Alphonse, 1853-1914; Hoover, J. Edgar(John Edgar), 1895-1972.; Scollard, Clinton.; Cornell University.Class of 1884.; Explorers' Club.; International Society for Personal Identification.; Shrine of Our Lady of Lourdes.; Shrine of St. Anne de Beaupre.; Shrine of St. Joseph du Mont-Royal.
Subjects:
Bertillon system.; Crime and criminology.; Fingerprints.; World War, 1939-1945
Places:
New York (N.Y.); Fulton (N.Y.)
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Even though this collection includes #41-4-833 and #41-4-1282, they are obsolete - please use collection #3214 when requesting boxes
SERIES LIST
Series I. Correspondence, Papers, and Miscellaneous
Boxes 1-9
Series II. Photographs
Box 10, oversized (O/S) folders
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Correspondence, Papers, and Miscellaneous
  - Poems and Songs; 1937-1939, 1944, T.S.S. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence; 1935-1939, 1941, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence; 1923-1924, 1928-1929, 1935-1936, 1941, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, cards, memos; 1926-1928, 1933-1935, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    re: medicine, family, alumni affairs
  - Correspondence, cards, clippings; 1940-1941, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    re: medicine, family, contact lenses
  - Correspondence; 1938-1941 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Clippings - James Burke; 1940 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Clippings; 1937-1946 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Clippings; 1932, 1938, 1943-1946 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Magazine clippings (APS); 1944, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper Clippings (APS); 1942, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Atlantic Daily News; 1912 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Medical Publicationns - periodicals, pamphlets; 1920's, 1938-1943, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous Publications - pamphlets; 1922, 1938, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Misc. Publications - pamphlets; 1938, 1941-1946 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Misc. Publications - pamphlets; 1906, 1939, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Dr. Andrew J. Gilmour; 1905-1913 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Pamphlets, rough drafts, typescripts and manucripts
  - Alpha Mu Phi Omega Medical Fraternity - Pamphlet, corres.; 1923 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Associated Physicians of Long Island - Clippings, pamphlets; 1941 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Biloxi, Miss.; 1933, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Post cards, pamphlets, corres., clippings
  - Adventurer's Club - corres., pamphlet; 1943 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Plaza Trust Company - pamphlets, corres.; 1928, 1931, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - British War Relief - clippings, corres.; 1941 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - A Visit to Mrs. Abby W. Stevens - corres., pamphlets, maps; 1933 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - A Visit to Mrs. Abby W. Stevens - corres., daily account; 1934 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Trip to Washington D.C. - corres., clippings; 1935 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Clinton Scollard - corres., cards, pamphlets; 1929-1933 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Snapshots taken by J.D. McIntyre (bound volume); 1898 (Box 2)
  - Medical Records, 7th Army Corps, Panama Park, Fl. (bound volume); 1898 (Box 2)
    Records, notes, autopsy reports
  - Notebooks - misc. notes and addresses (bound volumes, 5); n.d. (Box 2)
  - Vacation to Haines Falls, NY (4 folders); 1935 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Corres., clippings, post cards, daily accounts
  - Vacation to Haines Falls, NY (4 folders); 1928 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Corres., photographs, daily accounts, cards, clippings
  - Memorabilia - cards, printed material; 1923, 1932, 1939, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Memorabilia - menu, cards, printed material; 1920's-1940's (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Memorabilia - misc. printed material; 1920's, 1937, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Holton-Arms school - 30 year Anniversary; 1931 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Corres., cards, menu, periodical, speeches
  - Christmas Cards and Greetings (2 folders); 1940-1941 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - A Pilgrimage to the Shrine of St. Joseph Du Mont-Royal - post cards; 1932 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - A Pilgrimage to the Shrine of Sainte Anne De Beaupre - post cards, photographs, corres.; 1921 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - A Pilgrimage to the Shrine of Our Lady of Lourdes - post cards; 1931 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - A Pilgrimage to the Shrine of Dr. W.M. Locke - photographs; 1932 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Bookplate, Ida Wilkinson Harlan - corres., photograph, clippings; 1921-1932 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Bookplates designed by Henry de Forest; 1910-1940 (Box 4, Folder 6a)
  - Luther Rice Dickinson vs. Lee de Forest - corres., stock certificate; 1931 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Vacation to Willoughby Lake, Wesymore, Vermont; 1932 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Trip to Washington D.C. - corres., post cards, memorabilia; 1936 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Trip to Pelenville and Return - post cards, corres.; 1935 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Culver's Lake, NJ with Mrs. Margaret Colman; 1935-1936 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Trip to Hartford - corres., momentos; 1935-1936 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Valentine Material - pamphlets, corres., clippings; 1929 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Birthday Greetings - corres., cards, lists; 1936 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Christmas, Birthday, Correspondence; 1935-1936 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Valentine - corres., account, poem (M.C.); 1932 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Christmas, Birthday, Gifts and Acknowledgements; 1931 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Christmas Cards and Greeting; 1933-1934 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Color Blindness - printed material, pamphlets, corres.; 1931 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Arches by John E. Phifer - pamphlet, t.s. copy; n.d. (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Columbia Univ., Commencement Day; 1945 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Programs, clippings, name cards, corres., peridocials
  - Columbia Univ., Alumni Day - corres., pamphlets; 1938-1939 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Columbia Univ., Commencement Day - corres., programs, clippings; 1939 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Columbia Univ., Commencement Day - corres., programs, clippings; 1936 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Columbia Univ., Alumni Day - corres.; 1936 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Columbia Univ., College of Physicians and Surgeons Alumni Dinners - programs, menus; 1905, 1910, 1911 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Columbia Univ., College of Physicians and Surgeons Alumni Association (5 folders); 1936-1938 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Corres., lists, clippings, cards
  - Columbia Univ., College of Physicians and Surgeons New York Alumni Association; 1939 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Corres., constitution, by-laws
  - Columbia Univ., Alumni Affairs - corres., misc. printed material; 1914, 1923, 1927, 1939, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Columbia Univ., College of Physicians and Surgeons Class Lists - (2 unbound volumes); 1865-1936 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Cornell Univ., "Month at Cornell, May 1926;" 1926 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Corres., research notes, case history, pamphlets
  - Trip to Ithaca - daily account (t.s.); 1930 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Description of 9.5 hour auto trip from NYC to Ithaca and preparations and mention of Hudson ferry crossing.
  - Cornell Univ., Inauguration of Edmund Ezra Day - corres., cards, memos; 1937 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Cornell Univ., Professorship for Medical Research - corres.; 1920 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - misc. printed material, pamphlet, t.s. article; 1921, 1934-1935, 1938-1939 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Finger-Print and Identification Magazine; 1938 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - "The First Finger-Print File in the United States," article by H.P. de Forest; 1938 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, (3 folders) - lists, pamphlet, clippings, cards; 1937-1938 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Evolution of Dactyloscopy in the United States, Acknowledements 1931-1932 - corres., clippings; 1931-1933, [ -1935] (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Finger Print Expert State Civil Serve Commission - corres., M.C. Exam; 1916 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Dactyloscopy - Castellanos Correspondence (Finger Printing Inmates in Insane Asylums); 1930 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    Corresp., t.s. and c.c. report
  - Personal Identification, Identification by Comparison of Roentgenograms of Nasal Accessory Sinuses May 27, 1927, J[ournal of the] A.M.A. - magazine article (t.s. and c.c.); 1927 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Dactyloscopy - Bibliography of Finger Prints - Other Sources 1931; 1931 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Personal Identification, Correspondence in re: Manuscript: First Finger Print Bureaus of the United States - corres.; 1930-1931 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Dactyloscopy, Bibliography of Fingerprints, books in the library of Henry Pelouze de Forest; 1931 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - "The Evolution of Dactyloscopy in the United States" - rough drafts (t.s.); 1903 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Dactyloscopy - Dactyloscope correspondence in re: the Dactyloscope which was invented by Henry P. de Forest, M.D., in 1912; 1924-1929, 1930-1933 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Personal Identification, "Invisible Finger and Palm Prints," Dr. Eug. Stockis; 1911 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Personal Identification, "Development of Fingerprints on Paper," Eug. Stockis, M.D.; n.d. (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Personal Identification, "The One Finger Classification," Dr. Eug. Stockis; 1914 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - "The Evolution of Dactyloscopy in the United States," Lecture with Lantern Slides by Henry P. de Forest, M.D.; 1936 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Corres., lists, reports, fingerprint cards
  - The Seventeenth Annual Convention of the International Association for Identification; 1931-1932 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Corres., clippings, slide listing, pamphlet
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation, John Edgar Hoover Corres., M.C. notes; 1936 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - The Testimonial Dinner to Henry Pelouze de Forest, M.D., Jan. 26, 1935, Hotel McAlpine - corres., clippings, notes; 1935 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    -Contains a photographic reproduction of the first set of prints ever taken for official us by the US Government
  - Dactyloscopy - Reprints of Charles Stockley Collins - These three reprints were recieved in Jan. 1932, 1921, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Numbered list of persons to whom "Evolution of Dactyloscopy in the United States" was sent; n.d. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Evolution of Dactyloscopy in the United States - corres. with the printers, the Beil and Evans Co., 850 Market St., Youngstwn, Ohio; 1931 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - "The First Fingerprint Bureau in the United States," original mss. copy (carbon sent to printer); 1931-1932 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Dactyloscopy - Bibliography; also, personal identity - bibliography; 1916, 1917 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Dactyloscopy - Ernest Reichert - Fingerprint Game - corres., charts for game; 1942-1943 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Personal Identification - International Association for Identification - "Sparks from the Anvil" - Periodical; 1933-1934 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence (3 folders); 1920's, 1930-1937, 1938-1940, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - The Evoultion of Dactyloscopy in the United States - pamphlets, article, t.s.; 1930 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - de Forest Articles - articles, t.s., pamphlets; 1931-1933 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Personal Identification, "Wanted Posters" - broadsides, m.c. letters; 1936, 1938, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Dactyloscopy; n.d. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Criminology, Reference Material (2 folders); 1916, 1926, 1931, 1935-1938 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    Pamphlets, reprints, articles, t.s., periodicals
  - Crime (2 folders) - clippings; 1931-1938 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Cornell banner, MU-1176
- Series II. Photographs
  -Photographs for Lectures on Criminology, Fingerprints, and the Bertillon System
  - Bertillon System; Police Headquarters, Dresdon; 1907 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Police Dept., Dresdon, Uniform of High Officers (Capt., Lieut., Sergt.) (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Police Dept., Dresdon, Uniform of patrolmen of various grades (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Impersonation; Voight, (Capt. von Koepenick) who in officer's uniform arrested the mayor and took the city funds in Koepenick, Germany. (New York Tribune, 1908 ) (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Criminal Photography - Forgery of Check, original signature smoothly outlined (Box 10, Folder 1)
    Forgery showing tremor due to slow tracing. Also signature showing tremor of old age with shapely marked corners at end of writing. Plates XXXIV, XXXV, XXXVI. Paul, Friedrich "Handbuch der Kriminalistisohen Photographie"
  - Forgery: Rible said to have been Martin Luther's sold for a large sum of money. Entire book was a forgery. (Berlin, Sept. 19, 1907 ) (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Bertillon System. Tripod used for criminal work in photographing rooms, dead bodies, etc.: will hold apparatus and a man. (Folded for transportation, Sept. 19, 1907 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Bertillon System. Giant camera, showing method of use. Sept. 19, 1907 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Bertillon System. (a) Unknown woman who has forgotten her own identity. (b) Unknown man, identity desired (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Habitual Criminal. Convicted and punished 67 times in the Tyrole, Austria. Four photographs at different ages. 4 Bertillon pictures: 1906, Innsbruck; 1908, Bozen; 1909, Meran; 1910, Innsbruck (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Criminal Photography. Giant camera showing position of murdered girl, Hamburg. Plate XXVIII. Paul, Friedrich "Handbuch der Kriminalistisohen Photographie" (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Lust murder (Lustmord) from the criminal records of Hamburg, showing the position of the body and its surroundings. Plate XVII. Paul, Friedrich "Handbuch der Kriminalistisohen Photographie" (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Bertillon System. Showing cigar store and corpse of a murdered woman killed by an axe-blow at back of head as she turned to get cigars for the criminal. 1903 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Showing corpse as it was found the morning after the murder. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Bertillon System. Body of murdered Insurance Agent Hartmann, as it was found after being exhumed. Dresdon, Sept. 1907 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Bertillon System. Bodies of unidentified men kept in cabinet of Police Headquarters. All were identified after some days or weeks. Berlin, Sept. 19, 1907 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Bertillon System. Profile and front view of unidentified woman found drowned. Kept on exhibitation in cabinets of Police Headquarters instead of in morgue. Body identified. Dreson, Sept. 11-19, 1907 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Bertillon System. Details of stand made to show place and date upon the negative itself, movable numeral used: (4 illus.), Dresdon, Sept. 11-19, 1907 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Bertillon System. Card register for men, Dresdon, Sept. 1907 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Bertillon System. Room for Daktyloskopie. Cabinet with work table. Finger-print stand. Framed instruction cards. Dresdon, Sept. 11-19, 1907 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Bertillon System. Finger-prints of Henry P. de Forest, Police Surgeon, New York City, on glass. Photo by obliquely transmitted light. Berlin, Sept. 28, 1907 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Bertillon System. Two finger prints made by the same criminal. Same enlarged. Burlgary. Crispi Case, New York City (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Bertillon System. Portion of safe door, showing experimental finger-prints. Value entirely destroyed by retouching of negative. "New York World" 1911. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Finger-prints on cards used in the Fulton Savings Bank, and in about one hundred other banks in the State of New York for identification of the depositors, June 12, 1912. Presented by William J. Lovejoy, Cashier of Fulton Savings Bank (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Personal Identity. The veins of the back of the hand as a means of identification as suggested by Prof. Arrigo Tamassia, Professor of Legal Medicine at the Univerity of Padua, Italy. Legend under each one of the four photographs (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Criminal Photography. Collection of weapons and instruments from the Criminal Museum at Christiana, Norway, 1912 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Criminal Photography (Murder case). Amilon murdered for robbery, 1901 and put in a barrel. Murderer, Frederick Gustave Emmanuel Hanson sentenced to life imprisonment and died there in 1908. Stockholm, Sweden (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Criminal Photography (Murder case). Girl baby, nine months old, strangled Apr. 4, 1912, at Ralambstorg, near Stockholm, Sweden, by her father Earl Ludwig Nordahl, a shoe-maker. He concealed the baby in some underbrush near the road just outside of the town (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Review of Bureau of Police. Dept. of Public Safety, Philadelphia, Oct. 1910, at Philadelphia Ball Park (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Police Department New York., Uniform: Rogues' Gallery (in colors), plate 52a Police Dept. Annual 1911 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Daktyloscopie. Finger Print Bureau, Christiania, Norway, 1906 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Bureau of Physical Examination, Civil Service Commission. Joseph A. Ruddy taking fingerprints of candidates. Picture taken by Brosnan, Bd. W.S., Dec. 12, 1915 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Daktyloscopie. Bertillon System. Tripod set up with camera in position. Berlin, Sept. 19, 1907 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Portrait of Mary E. Holland, (nee) Trowel, born Urbana, Iowa, Feb. 20, 1857, died Wesley Memorial Hospital Mar. 27, 1915, (Chicago, Ill.) Presented by J. Herbert Taylor, Mar. 30, 1915 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Daktyloscopie. Portrait of Johannes Evangelista Purkinje, 1787-1869. (This name is pronounced: Poor - keen - ye). In "Biology and its makers;" by W.A. Lacy, N.Y.: Holt, 1915, p.267 (Best portrait found) (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Daktyloscopie. "Finger-prints" of an armless vagrant, Scientific American, June 8, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Portrait of Sir William J. Hersohel. (In colors) (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Portrait of Sir William J. Hersohel. (from a recent photograph from life) (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Tattooing a Burmese boy (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Tattooing (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Unidentified, including photographs of Sir Edward Henry, the Pacific Ocean near La Jolla, and misc. photographs on criminology (Box 10, Folder 10-15)
  - Dr. H.P. de Forest tells of Famous Falley Seminary," scrapbook of clippings of article from Oswego Palladium-Times; 1943 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Illustrations of James Johnson and H.P. de Forest used in Finger Print and Identification Magazine (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Bertillon, Alphose. Autographed portrait of Alphonse Bertillon, Chief of the Paris Secret Service Police, Died Feb. 17, 1914. Presented by M. Bertillon to Henry P. de Forest, M.D., Sept. 13, 1912, O/S Folder 1; 25 x 30.5 cm; Mounted on board.
    -was originally in Box 10 Folder 4
    Gelatin silver prints
  - A composite of mug shots, Bertillon measurements and fingerprints of Will West and William West, an infamous case that showed the importance of a fingerprint system over the Bertillon system, 1901-1904, O/S Folder 2
    Digital composite created by RMC staff to illustrate one of Bertillon's cases. The original items used for this composite are located at the National Archives (Will West, Leavenworth Inmate #3426, and William West, Leavenworth Inmate #2626; ARC Identifier: 580698)